SPENCER TRUETT

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

(615) 972-3614

▼ STRUETT.DEVELOPER@GMAIL.COM

GITHUB.COM/SPENCERTRUETT

in LINKEDIN.COM/IN/SPENCER-TRUETT/

PROJECTS

MEDJOURNAL

FRONT-END CAPSTONE

MedJournal is a mobile-focused web application designed for users to easily access and log medical details in one convenient location. The app utilizes a variety of easy-to-use forms to record health data which is then dynamically populated on the chart below to provide a detailed overview of past recordings. All recordings can be edited and deleted from the list, dynamically effecting the chart as well. All charts can be viewed in the "Profile View" to give an overview of one's health to provide to a healthcare professional. The app also includes a Food Journal to record detailed information about meals and potential allergens. There is also a medication tracker to track if a medication has been taken for a given day. A timestamp is recorded when taken to provide the last time a medication was taken for a healthcare professional. Technologies used include React, Chart.js, Moment.js, and CSS

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE
NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

STUDIED MOLECULAR BIOLOGY
LIPSCOMB UNIVERSITY | 2011 - 2014

PROFILE

Born and raised in middle Tennessee, I began my college career at David Lipscomb University with the intentions of becoming a doctor. After server years of soul-searching, I decided that medicine was not where my heart truly was. I started teaching and performing music locally. My students have gone on to win numerous nationally-recognized awards and have spread out across the country, continuing on to a wide variety of careers. Ironically, it's one of those students who led me to Nashville Software School and, ultimately, my love of coding.

So I decided to try out a coding "jumpstart" at NSS, and I was immediately hooked. It was then that I jumped into the bootcamp with both feet and I'll never look back. Coding has been a nonstop journey of wondrous new endeavors, ambitious challenges to overcome, and marvelous discoveries to uncover. I've learned that the world of coding is filled with a never-ending plethora of new things to discover, which excites me to no end!

EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | NOV 2019 - MAY 2020

- Hands on application and experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, C#/.NET
- Built browser-based, full-stack applications.
- Utilized GitHub for source code version control and collaboration.
- Use and creation of multiple API's.
- Working with SCRUM methodology for team projects.

FREELANCE MUSICIAN/EDUCATOR

SELF-EMPLOYED | AUG 2012 - MAY 2018

- Performed vocal and instrumental percussion both locally and globally.
- Instructed students in private lessons and classroom settings across Middle Tennessee.
- Responsible for the coordination of parents and students for multiple school events.
- Created daily lesson plans while being able to respond to an agile work environment.

FREELANCE LEGAL COURIER

SELF-EMPLOYED | NOV 2014 - MAY 2018

- Delivered important legal documents on behalf of judges and lawyers throughout the Middle Tennessee
- Responsible for delivering in a timely manner.
- Expected to respond appropriately in a professional, legal setting.